A Guide to the List of Inhabitants of the Governor's Office, 1782-1785
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
List of inhabitants of the Governor's Office, 1782-1785
The Library of Virginia
34894
2.6 cubic feet (5 Boxes)
Virginia Office of the Governor
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available. Acquired prior to 1905.
Historical Information
Lists of inhabitants were collected in accordance with several acts of the General Assembly, particularly those of May 1782 (Chapter XXIII) and May 1784 (Chapter XXXVIII). The returns dated 1782 and 1783 are for inhabitants (i.e. 'souls'), while those dated in 1784 and 1785 are for buildings. Occassionally includes a covering letter or forwarding note.
Scope and Content
Lists of inhabitants, dated 1782 to 1785, for thirty-nine Virginia counties and the town of Williamsburg. Information found in the lists for 1782 and 1783 include the name of the head of the household, the number of white inhabitants, and the number of slaves. The lists for 1784 and 1785 include the heads of households, the number of whites, and the numbers of dwellng houses and "outhouses." Clerks of the county courts were responsible for collecting the lists from justices and transmitting them to the Governor. The exact disposition of the records after their transmittal to the Governor is unclear.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in alphabetical order order.
Contents List
- Lists of Inhabitants, 1782-1785.
  - Albemarle County, 1785. (Box 1)
  - Amelia County, 1782. (Box 1)
  - Amelia County, 1785. (Box 1)
  - Amherst County, 1783. (Box 1)
  - Amherst County, 1785. (Box 1)
  - Bedford County, 1783. (Box 1)
  - Charlotte County, 1782. (Box 1)
  - Charlotte County, 1783. (Box 1)
  - Chesterfield County, 1783. (Box 1)
  - Cumberland County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Cumberland County, 1784. (Box 2)
  - Essex County, 1783. (Box 2)
  - Fairfax County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Fairfax County, 1785. (Box 2)
  - Fluvanna County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Frederick County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Gloucester County, 1783. (Box 2)
  - Gloucester County, 1784. (Box 2)
  - Greenbrier County, 1783. (Box 2)
  - Greensville County, 1783. (Box 2)
  - Halifax County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Halifax County, 1785. (Box 2)
  - Hampshire County, 1782. (Box 2)
  - Hampshire County, 1784. (Box 2)